# Amirhosein Farhoodi

# Senior Frontend Developer

+989036330386

farhoodiamirhosein@gmail.com Linkedin



#### **SUMMA**

I'm an experienced front-end developer for more than 5 years and my main focus is Javascript. As a developer I always keep myself updated on new technologies. Not only am I always looking for new advancements in frontend technologies, but I also like to expand my knowledge on backend development and recently i'm working on blockchain (smart contract/web3) And I think it's wonderful, As a hobby I like skateboarding and that really refreshes my mind.

## **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Solidity.

**Core:** ReactJS, React Native, React Hooks and Context, Next JS, Redux, Telegraf JS, Express JS, Web3 and Smart contract.

**Testing:** Jest, React Testing Library.

**UI Libraries:** Styled Components, Ant Design, Pug, Draft.js, Responsive and Semantic UI, Tailwind, Bootstrap.

Other Libraries: React Query, Next Cookies,

Tooling: Git, VS Code, ESLint, TypeScript, Yarn, NPM, Prettier, Webpack, Babel, Github.

Network: RESTful HTTP, Socket.io, GraphQL, ETH Smart Contract.

**More:** DOM, Web APIs, PWA, Service Workers, SEO, Cross-browser Compatibility, Scrum, Agile, Jira, Zeplin, Figma.

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATES**

- Computer Diploma, Sazandegi
- Web Design, Tehran Institute of Technology
- Javascript course, Udemy platform / Jonas Schmedtmann
- Node js express js course, Udemy platform / Jonas Schmedtmann
- React js course, Udemy platform / Maximilian Schwarzmuller
- React native course, Udemy platform / Stephan Grider
- React js course, Kent C. Dodds
- **Testing course**, Kent C. Dodds

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Zencats, Freelance** - Senior Frontend developer

Oct 2021 - Present (5 mos)

Zencats is an under-construction platform in the NFT market.

- Working on the main SSR website using NextJs, Typescript and tailwind, Ethereum, and MetaMask libraries.
- Research and development Web3 and Ethereum network for blockchain requirements.
- Implementing features with openSea platform APIs.

Playtunity, Freelance - Senior Frontend developer

*Jul 2021 - Present (8 mos)* 

Playtunity is a platform for trading in-game items from various multiplayer games.

- Develop Product SSR website using NextJS, React-Redux, and Bootstrap
- Design and implement reusable components and logic for Playtunity utilizing React's custom hooks and components

Lawmingo, Freelance - Senior Frontend developer

Jan 2020 - Jul 2021 (1 yr, 7 mos)

<u>Lawmingo</u> is a legal platform for signing and arranging online contracts with more than 1 million users.

- Develop web applications acting as the admin panel of the system using ReactJS,
  TypeScript, React-Redux, and Bootstrap.
- Implement User-facing SSR website using NextJS, TypeScript, React-Redux, and Bootstrap.
- Research and development mobile application using React Native, TypeScript

**Takhfifan/Netbarg** - Frontend developer

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019 (1 yr, 1 mo)

<u>Takhfifan</u> and <u>Netbarg</u> are the merged e-commerce platforms for online shopping and selling discount coupons with more than 2 million users.

- Manage common admin panel for Netbarg and Takhfifan products such as web applications.
- I was Responsible for the maintenance of the main websites of the business, Netbarg, and Takhfifan, and for providing ideas for optimizing for thousands of visits per .

**Peeyade** - Frontend developer

Jan 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 yr, 11 mos)

Peeyade is a mobile and web application for city tourism in Tehran and it is where I started my career.

- Implement a SSR website with NextJS, React-Redux, and Bootstrap.
- DevelopedPeeyade main application with more than 200,000 users, uses React js, NextJS (SSR), Redux, Ant Design, Sass.
- Manage Peeyade admin panel is the CMS platform and back-office for all Peeyade's products such as web application, and marketing needs with about 200 local users.